David Thomas

Thiruvananthapuram Taluk, Kerala, India



in linkedin.com/in/djtin



djt.in7@gmail.com

Summary

Software Engineer with professional experience in building complete solutions with JavaScript/TypeScript and deploying them with popular options like AWS, Heroku or GCP.

Strong foundations in software architectural design and software engineering principles.

Able to adapt to any reasonable environment and deliver battle-tested software.

Experience



Experion Technologies

Apr 2020 - Present (5 months +)

🔇 Associate Software Engineer

Experion Technologies

Nov 2018 - Apr 2020 (1 year 6 months)

Software Engineering Trainee

Experion Technologies

Jul 2018 - Nov 2018 (5 months)

Education



Full Stack Web Development Certification, Computer Software Engineering 2017 - 2018

🛞 Mahatma Gandhi University, Kottayam

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science 2014 - 2018

Licenses & Certifications

Node.js: Microservices - LinkedIn

DevOps Foundations: Lean and Agile - LinkedIn

Advanced Python - LinkedIn

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (SAA-C01): 1 Cloud Services Overview (2019) - LinkedIn

Succeeding in Web Development: Full Stack and Front End - LinkedIn

Algorithmic Trading and Stocks Essential Training - LinkedIn

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (SAA-C01): 4 Compute Services - LinkedIn

- Node.js: Real-Time Web with Socket.IO LinkedIn
- in Learning Kubernetes LinkedIn
- Algorithmic Trading and Finance Models with Python, R, and Stata Essential Training LinkedIn
- TypeScript: Object-Oriented Programming LinkedIn
- in Node.js: Design Patterns LinkedIn
- in Node.js: Testing and Code Quality LinkedIn

Skills

Node.js • JavaScript • PostgreSQL • Data Structures • Database Design • Machine Learning • Web Development • Agile Project Management • Cloud Computing • Business Intelligence (BI)